Guide to the Newman Levy Archive ca. 1914-1960 MSS.041
Fales Library and Special Collections
Newman Levy Papers
circa 1914-1960
Fales Library and Special Collections
Levy, Newman, 1888-1966
MSS.041
3 Linear Feet in 7 boxes
Newman Levy (1888-1966) was a lawyer and author. The Newman Levy Papers inlcude manuscripts of his articles, book reviews, drama, fiction, verse, and materials related to an unpublished biography of Franklin P. Adams
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into six series:
Series I: Articles
Series II: Book Reviews
Series III: Drama
Series IV: Fiction
Series V: Verse
Series VI: Biographical materials collected by Franklin P. Adams for his biography of Levy.
Materials are arranged alphabetically within each series.
Missing Title
Series I: Articles
Series II: Book Reviews
Series III: Drama
Series IV: Fiction
Series V: Verse
Series VI: Biography of Franlin P. Adams
Provenance
The Newman Levy Papers were donated to NYU by The Players Club in December 1991.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of 7 boxes of manuscript material of articles, book reviews, drama, fiction, verse, and an unpublished biography of Franklin P. Adams, including some letters written to Levy by people who knew Adams.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Biographical Note
Newman Levy was born in 1888. His father was the well-known New York criminal lawyer Abraham Levy. Newman Levy graduated from New York University Law school in 1911, and practiced law until 1961. He was an assistant district attorney for New York County from 1916 to 1919. Levy also wrote light verse and skits for Broadway revues. His books inlcude Gay but Wistful and the autobiography My Double Life: Adventures in Law and Letters. He died in New York in 1966.
Articles.; Magazines (Periodicals); Drama.; Authors, American -- 20th century.; Fiction |y 20th century.; Reviews (document genre); Adams, Franklin P. (Franklin Pierce), 1881-1960
- Series I: Articles
  - The Affair Aurelio., undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The American Boy's Handy Book., undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology., undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "And a Good Judge Too--"., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Are We Getting the Law We Need?, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Art of Teaching to Give., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aunt Emma., undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Be Your Age., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Bill of Rights. [3 copies], undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - A Boy Who Made Good., undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Case of Genevieve Nicodemus., undated (Box 7, Folder 216)
  - Case of Thomas F. Mulligan. (Box 7, Folder 217)
  - The Clipping Bureau., undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clubs and Trumps., undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Constitution., undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Contribunion., undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Conversation Killer., undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Criminal Procedure in England., undated (Box 7, Folder 218)
  - Cuteisms. [2 copies], undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Danger, Men Working!, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Doctors and Doctors. [4 copies], undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Elegy., undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Everything is Under Control", undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Excuse it Please., undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - F.P.A., undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Female Superiority., undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Frenchy Case., undated (Box 7, Folder 219)
  - From Poll to Poll., undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Gallery Gods., undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Getting Away with Murder., undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Handbags for Men., undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Handbags for Men. [clipping from Woman's Day], May 1953 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Happy Days are Here Again., undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - The Happy Ending., undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - The High Imperial Potentate., undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - The House. [2 copies], undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - How to Not Read a Book., undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - How to Write Light Verse., undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - I Go Ahead., undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - If Lawyers Talked Like Lawyers. [clipping from Woman's Day], October 1954 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Impressions in a London Court., undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Jerome Kern., undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Law and the Sexes., undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Legal Aid., undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - The Lost Books of Livy., undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The Mantle of Mr. Gilbert., undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - A Matter of Form. [clipping from Woman's Day], October 1951 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Movie Law., undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - The Musical Comedy Business., undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - My Career as a Photographer., undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - My Memory System., undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Nature Imitates Art., undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - A Note on Divorce., undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - A Note on Gadgets., undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Nothing but the Truth., undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Of Thee I Sing., undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - On the Eight-Twelve., undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - On Reaching Middle Age., undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - On to Nicaragua., undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Onward and Upward with the Arts., undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Parties., undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Pearl., undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Progressive Educaton., undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Psycho-Analysis., undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - A Review of the Past Legal Season., undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - "Rimes are so Scarce"., undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Riot at the Opera House., undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Sam Feldman., undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - The Sartorial Revolution., undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - A Second Chance. [by Jonah Cunningham, pseud.], undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - "Season to Taste"., undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Shakespeare as a Humorist., undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Some Comments on Hospitality., undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - "Sticks and Stones May Break my Bones--"., undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - The Strange Case of Gregory Benson., undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Suggestions for Article on Have the Picturesque Lawyers Disappeared., undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Table Talk., undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - There Aren't Any Santa Clauses., undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - "They Made Me What I Am Today"., undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - A Treasury of Gilbert and Sullivan/Notes & Commentary., undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - The War of the Sexes [by Jonah Cunningham, pseud.], undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - What I Remember., undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Would You Defend a Man if You Knew He was Guilty?, undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Series II: Book Reviews
  - Brothers in Law, by Henry Cecil., undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Friends at Court, by Henry Cecil., undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - The Story of my Life, by Clarence Darrow., undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - For the Defense, the Life of Sir Edward Marshall Hall., undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Confessions of an Un-Common Attorney, by Reginald L. Hine., undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
- Series III: Drama
  - The Happy Hypocrite. [operetta], undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - The Happy Hypocrite., undated (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - The Judiciary Committee. [musical], undated (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - The Lalique Vase: A Television Play., undated (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - The Lalique Vase., undated (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Long Island., undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Lucky Seven: A Musical Cartoon. [musical], undated (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - "May it Please the Court--". [musical play], undated (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - "May it Please the Court--". [musical play], undated (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - "May it Please the Court--". [revised script], undated (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - "May it Please the Court". [music score], undated (Box 7, Folder 221)
  - A Modern Rip Van Winkle., undated (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Off the Record., undated (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Poor Richard., undated (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Skin Deep, a Television Play., undated (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - They Will Do It. [musical comedy], undated (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - [Untitled Play - Incomplete.], undated (Box 3, Folder 100)
- Series IV: Fiction
  - Adventures of Alice., undated (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - An Afternoon of a Judge [also titled Judge Beasely Takes a Plunge]., undated (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - The Age of Specialization., undated (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Alice at the News Stand., undated (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - All Work and No Play., undated (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Amanda., undated (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - At Home with a Celebrated Lawyer., undated (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - At Home with a Famous Doctor., undated (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - The Battle of the South., undated (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - A Bed Time Story., undated (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Billings Buys a Button., undated (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Billings Discusses Broadcasting., undated (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Billings Discusses Murder., undated (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Billings Goes Whimsical., undated (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Billings Has Another Idea., undated (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Billings Writes a Hit., undated (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Brooms are Obsolete Now., undated (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Burglary a la Mode., undated (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - The Case of Ben Grogan., undated (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - The Consultation., undated (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Death and Taxes., undated (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Fame., undated (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - "A Famous Lawyer at Home"., undated (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Football Game., undated (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Gertie and Tom., undated (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Good Morning, Judge., undated (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - The Godfus Mystery., undated (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Graham Gilbert (?) [Prison story]., undated (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - The Hall of Fame., undated (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - The Hepworth Vase., undated (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - His Mother's Husband., undated (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Hitler Goes to Heaven., undated (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Horace and the Talking Frog., undated (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Incompetent and Immaterial., undated (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Interview with an Ectoplasm., undated (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - An Interview wit a Prominent Author., undated (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Isabella's Jewels., undated (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - It Struck Me as Extremely Odd., undated (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - John Sexton., undated (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - The Joke Business / with TLS to & from The Stage., undated (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Jury Duty., undated (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Lindergarten., undated (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - King Lear (up to date)., undated (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - The Life of the Party., undated (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - The Little Fellow., undated (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Love on Forty-Ninth Street., undated (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Macbeth (As Eugene O'Neill Might Have Written It)., undated (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - The Magpie., undated (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - The Man Who Read the Ads., undated (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - The Man Who Read the Ads., undated (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Mavoureen., undated (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - The Merchant of Venice (As Shakespeare Might Have Written it To-Day)., undated (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - The Modern Drama., undated (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Moman Pruiett., undated (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - The Most Beautiful Princess. [in the World Woman's Day], December 1949 (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Mournful Numbers., undated (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - Mr. Leeming's Law Suit., undated (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - Mr. Shakespeare Goes to Town., undated (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Mr. Twickham's Birthday., undated (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Mrs. Epman's Elopement., undated (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - The Mudington Pearl Mystery., undated (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - Murder by Imagination., undated (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - My Favorite Race., undated (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - A New Christmas Carol., undated (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - The New Education., undated (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - Nigel Armstrong., undated (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - No Child is Cute After the First Half Hour [Woman's Day]., Feb. 1957 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Nor Iron Bars a Cage., undated (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - The Old Man Lay Dying., undated (Box 5, Folder 169)
  - Old Man Baker, by Louisa Craig Peabody., undated (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - On the Air., undated (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - One of the Finest., undated (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - Operation Waffle Iron., undated (Box 5, Folder 173)
  - Othello (In the Manner of Bernard Shaw)., undated (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - The Other Side of the Moon., undated (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Pistols for Two., undated (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - Paul Revere., undated (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - Peters Versus the Interborough., undated (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - The Prince's Christening., undated (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - Red Hot Daddy., undated (Box 5, Folder 180)
  - Romeo and Juliet (In the Manner of Booth Tarkington)., undated (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - Salesmanship., undated (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - The Shins of his Father., undated (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - Skin Deep is Plenty., undated (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - A Spot of Paris., undated (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - A Stitch in Time is Worth Two in the Bush., undated (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Stuffed Shirt., undated (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - The Summing Up., undated (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - System., undated (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - The Trial of Queen Caroline., undated (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - Voodoo in Connecticut., undated (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - [Untitled - partial], undated (Box 5, Folder 192)
- Series V: Verse
  - Abroad Thoughts from Home., undated (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - All God's Chillun Got a Code., undated (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - A Ballad of Lampedusa., undated (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Bills., undated (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - The Laws Delays., undated (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Local Pride., undated (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Poems., undated (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Poems., undated (Box 7, Folder 220)
  - Song of a Tired Liberal., undated (Box 5, Folder 200)
- Series VI: Biography of Franklin P. Adams
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 6, Folder 201)
  - Tms. Biography of Franklin Pierce Adams, pp. 1-116., undated (Box 6, Folder 202)
  - Tms. Biography of... pp. 117-217., undated (Box 6, Folder 203)
  - Tms. Biography of... pp. 218-304., undated (Box 6, Folder 204)
  - Tms. Biography of... [revisions & notes] (Box 7, Folder 222)
  - Correspondence from FPA to: Davis, Mrs. [1931] Wise, Florence. [1914], 1931, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 205)
  - Correspondence from FPA to: Izard, Forrest., 1941-1949 (Box 6, Folder 206)
  - Correspondence about FPA from: Aarons - Kiernan, undated (Box 6, Folder 207)
  - Correspondence about FPA from: Lawrence - Walker, undated (Box 6, Folder 208)
  - The Conning Tower - Dinner & Program., undated (Box 6, Folder 209)
  - Keep Your Rabbits Rabbi, We Have Rabbits of Our Own [music]., undated (Box 6, Folder 210)
  - Newspaper clippings by or about FPA., undated (Box 6, Folder 211)
  - Pictorial., undated (Box 6, Folder 212)
  - The Players Programs., undated (Box 6, Folder 213)
  - Tear Sheets from The Conning Tower Book., undated (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - Untermeyer, Louis [in The Conning Tower, 1936]: "Ballade of the Prime ecessity" "Ballade of Contention", undated (Box 6, Folder 215)